hello and welcome to our project brazing
on together tech project radians we get
together and concentrate on one
particular project this one being our
project so that's a little a little
different but we have the project holder
give us the aspirations that they would
most like to get out of the hour and
then we brainstorm to the best of our
ability how to fulfill those aspirations
and then it's on the project holder to
actually follow through with them it's a
little different it all is gonna play
the project hold or even though we all
are into the meta project so if you can
explain a bit what together tech is what
the meta project of projects is and then
what the aspirations are for today and
then maybe then I can add some if you
want sure sounds good and unlike other
sessions if I miss something in the
description feel free to chime in
because that's actually an option here
so together Tech is commonly called game
B projects in Facebook and on YouTube it
is called together tech we have also
called that the meta project if you hear
us talking about that in other videos
and we call it the meta project because
it's a project about projects so for
example I've got wiki election Bentley
has recent score I think Jubilee
considers idea cafe sort of your year
project right solution Aires at the
moment but idea and the idea is that
while there's unique parts to each
project there's also a lot of
commonality especially when you get into
apps that have a lot of sort of a
similar approach like wiki election and
recent score where it's kind of defense
making and trying to figure stuff out
and there's elements that will need to
be shared across projects things like
trust that was a big example for me
where it's trying to figure out what
does trust mean to the public and how
does an organization sort of garner
trust and keep it not did damage each
application and any research around that
can be usable by anyone else who would
with a project and then as well all of a
sort of more boring stuff that I think
project owners don't typically get too
excited about working on like C
marketing parts and be running the
coffee and all that the same sort of
thing that again not all project owners
will have and
ones that don't have how can we sort of
help supplement each other skills and
how you know as a group how can we say
oh I figured out how to solve a certain
problem that I think all of these these
projects or at least all you know a lot
of them will end up habit that will end
up being a lot of different things and
that's part of what we'll get into here
is maybe did there I'm sure they'll end
up being some things that were like that
sounds great
probably not the MVP so the aspiration
since that's I guess where I I'm headed
is to figure out what the MVP or the
Minimum Viable Product is for together
text so if like as a text solution as an
app online let's say you know it's
together text calm what does that look
like what is it actually offering people
who have projects and what is it
offering people who don't have projects
but are you know interested in helping
with existing projects and anything else
that is necessary in that kind of an
ecosystem is that I did nothing wrong
is that yeah it's a good aspiration
we're looking for the MVP and so I just
can't forget back to that aspiration
when I'm like coming up with my
billion-dollar ideas and people what and
the nice thing about the V MVP and this
conversation because they always end up
with that okay that's great but not MVP
is of course a we're recording it so
it's easy to go back but it's meant as
you can also sort of build up the
roadmap you can say oh that's that's an
awesome feature I you know that we
didn't think of it until now
probably not MVP but we definitely want
it and just I guess a little bit of
context this is coming about because I'm
in the process of writing up the specs
for wiki election to get sort of MVP
coded during the they covet 19 lock down
and I figured like my review of sort of
day 2 apps of what would he election at
least the MVP might look like and
together tech there's a lot of
similarities and they're sort of like
not with how the actual end databases
design but all of your basic stuff right
and luck registering a user and
displaying information on a page and sir
so the goal is I sort of won't want to
create like an earliest an early version
of something like that that is neither
together tech or were collections I sort
of get an idea for how much it costs and
then build it out to the point where
it's got all the features that are
shared between wiki elections and
together tech and then I would split it
off and say here's the wiki election
version and actually building up that
that database and then also use that
code split to now start building
together tech so that's sort of where
this came from
is we'll be building the first part just
as a part of what wiki election and the
sort of copying and pasting that and
starting a project for together tech
based on what that project is at that
point in time if that makes sense but my
mic was needed um I would like to just
mention that we right now have been
trying our minimal Viable Product which
is the Facebook group itself and it is
not working as well as I would have
liked as far as people participating
putting up their videos commenting
offering suggestions coming to the
solution reasons coming to the idea cafe
is on our projects and I don't know if
we want to spend any time brainstorming
how to improve that or you only want to
spend time looking at like creating our
own tech and what that would look like I
guess what I would suggest is that we we
talk about what go back kind of first
principles
what do we need in our projects and how
do we want to go about doing that rather
than I think there's a temptation to
think about what we think the community
needs so I like right hear from you guys
with which I'll need your projects yeah
I think the three of us will be able to
give a pretty good insight in what
people who have projects might want out
of something like together tech the part
that we don't have that we'll take a
stab at is live the only ones here he is
what someone who doesn't have a project
but might want to help with the project
what we feel that they might want that's
sort of our two main group
so that would be using an app like this
and then I guess dat
theoretically on that same vein help
project owners to help each other
which kind of end up becoming Disney the
same thing of somebody helping where the
project that's not theirs whether or not
I think we can actually because we're
both project holders for our own project
but we're also potential participants at
each other's projects as we know and so
can you like take and put on the hats
right like what would what would get if
I'm asking a question about solution
raising what would get you to do what
I'm asking
versus you know for first together
attack because for solution raising I
have the same like problem as our
Facebook group it's only a Facebook
group at the moment and then I'm
scheduling calls there's a spreadsheet
but no one's filling it out so that I
get seven people on a call but I think
there's one person on and how to
actually deal with that without people
coming at participating in the why
aren't you participating right and and
what would get you to participate what
would give you the most value and so my
issue with solution raising is basically
our issue with together attack of leg
this could this is only as powerful as
the people who show up and participate
yeah and then figure it out the next
piece from there and then having people
the individuals feeling like they have
quote like that their voice matters that
their ideas matter that like this is a
space this isn't about it being just
mine it is about you can create your own
solution raise it it doesn't have to be
on my schedule what would get you to
participate in the ones I have right
like what is creating the communication
that isn't hierarchical down it's not
I'm in charge and I'm running everything
it's how how do you offer your solutions
in a way that we can all yes and right
and and the ones that absolutely won't
work maybe not know
okay I think on the note you you have
mentioned something about like should we
talk about the Facebook group I'm trying
to do it in Facebook and sort of the
issues with that and I think that is I
like when we touch on that because I
agree that we should that sort of
becomes a what does face will give us
and we know where where can we find an
MVP feature in there and then also what
is it not doing that maybe we can say
from the get-go we want to make sure
that it does this and that is one of the
benefits of MVP is it's now a completely
separate thing that we can have our
control over trying to figure out you
know how do we actually get people
involved how do we make sure that if we
put a message if somebody does something
that the appropriate people are informed
because that's part of the issue of
Facebook is just the torrent of
information that comes at you and of
course they just don't show you
everything unless somebody wants to pay
to post that that's kind of intentional
on that part so so there are two things
I think we can be doing further together
tech Facebook and I can take these for
solution racing one of which is just
like we've said many times talking about
the algorithm and like comment and talk
like things that you want here's how you
help it grow right but also in the game
be admin because we have our own
Indiamen group for having conversations
but there's only 11 of us so it never is
gonna reach the algorithm having an
actually explicit if this group is
important to you and you want to see
these things over whatever else is in
your newsfeed turn on notifications to
all right and so that will that will
bring it up for the importance of you if
it is important to you and then also for
that post in particular through the
comments and stuff so everyone sees this
so they know to do it maybe even just
saying now this project is it is
important to me I actually more want to
see my high school friends updates right
or like what is just having the comments
and the conversation having the likes
and then also just explaining how to
turn on the notifications right yeah I
think that make sense
I think that's yeah that's definitely a
good thing to make sure that we are
taking as full advantage of you know I
guess what I call like the proto
type as we can so if it's doing things
like hey let's actually turn on the
notifications so that we can get more
people actually showing up to sessions
and seeing the posts I think that makes
all of it sense and then sorry the other
thing also I've been doing is like when
I post the one with the stream large
yard link I go back in and edit it to
put the actual link and that or I delete
it if i birdied on that twice so that
it's not a bunch of stuff in our
newsfeed that you don't need because
it's outdated and then whatever the most
precedent like this one I made the
announcement for today so that if
someone's on that page that's gonna be
what their scenes and you know what I
mean if we have a project raising and
having that person's explanation of
their project possibly painted and then
happy an hour to under it right so
people are like for the week that's like
just picking what is the most pressing
and having that be the announcement
that's right I think and I mean this is
partially of me because I was one of
post it but we also only talked about
posting it yesterday is may be figuring
out cadence we're posting more than a
day before here's the net that gives the
algorithm a chance to show up to a few
more people because I know I'm
constantly seeing posts you know of
people that I would the high school
where there was like they posted that
five years ago and I'm just now seeing
that yeah absolutely
and then I cuz I'm not a tech person
Facebook is where I'm like I can maybe
run a Facebook group and we're figuring
out the problems troubleshooting for
that but for the actual if we're
concentrating on the coding of an MVP I
don't necessarily know what you need to
be able to do that because like why is
it how is it different than the Facebook
group as far as what do you need to know
you create your own algorithm or no
algorithm right yes so a big part of it
is just trying to figure out like I
guess you would start with what problems
you're trying to solve which we sort of
started with and then you you your next
layer down kind of becomes the almost
how you'd figured that you're solving
them or like particular features that
you think might solve it right so an
example might be how are we going to go
into to notify people if you're a member
and you're somebody who says
I'm interested in reading score and book
election which I think will end up
having to be a feature of some way to it
you know indicate and interest in a
project if that project has something
going on how do we want to notify people
look is that just an email is that a
text message we give people the ability
right like what is the MVP I was at MVP
is probably just email and you can
technically kind of fake a text message
through through email as well but then
it becomes what saw what we need and
what is the MVP versus where do we maybe
want to end up like it's pretty easy to
see if we have a full-fledged app that's
where okay maybe it also becomes it have
on the phone and then it starts to come
up with notifications on the phone
that's something that probably not MVP
but we'd probably hate to end up there
yeah I think that notification of what
is going on actually is MVP is like
because the Facebook group is the I mean
but it's like how do we get people to
know if we're not messaging everybody if
we're not doing things within Facebook
and it's email and text message and
people to opt-in to say yes when I have
things in this category I want to know
whether right maybe you only wanna know
about the things in education or in
recent sense-making right like maybe and
figure you know out that piece of it
like what how do we get that permission
from people and how do we get their text
message and then if we have their text
message and you know how do we actually
send out those notifications because
that's not my strong suit right yeah and
the the how to do of we don't have to
worry about that yet like aside from the
let's do it for email because the other
ways are a bit you know too difficult
what's even that it's not necessarily a
part of the actual MVP design that's
just be guessing what we'll end up
having to do alright so some form of
notification and a way for members to
like choose what they're notified on I
think does that make sense as sort of a
baseline we've it has to have that or
why are we even doing this if you have
to go checking every day to see what
what's new that's not very good yeah
that is the need that this fulfilling is
in our projects we want more
participation what's the core need that
I mean in my mind the cordoning is to
sort of help get projects off the ground
and help them get the help they need
yeah you know so it's like which might
be a good place to start because these
notifications are more for the like the
helpers I guess you might call them as
opposed to like the project owners and
so like for a project owner what did
they need what's sort of the bare
minimum for example to explain your
project there's gonna have to be some
sort of a profile to say you know here's
what reason score is are you interested
you'll have to give some sort of an
intro it's just I guess I don't I don't
think we have a really good phrasing and
I think we're jumping down the design
path when we're not sure I don't have a
clear understanding that that's the most
pressing need what's I mean so that's
what we've talked about in the past
that's how we kind of envisioned this
product but the work I think we're doing
it out of order so what's the main thing
that our individual projects need that
were that we want to fulfill if that's
getting other participants then then
fine let's talk about notifications but
if we all need marketing then maybe we
could take a marketing course together
and we could post that on gave me
projects and do that as a group of
through Facebook I mean I don't have a
clear understanding of what we're trying
to solve we're still talking solutions
but we don't have the problem outline
right so I I guess the main problem that
I struggle with in projects is just what
I call that skill gap right so like I've
got certain skills when it comes like
I've got a history
in product management so that's in
theory means I've got a certain skill
set but for example I'm not a developer
so anything to do with so you know like
the the specs they had a written will
end up having to be did you know good
good done over with an actual developer
and then built out and an tested I'm
also you know not good at marketing so
if somebody's good at at marketing
and while I'm open to doing things like
taking courses I also don't think that
everyone will want to sort of have every
skillset necessary and so it's to be
able to sort of I guess list the things
that I would need help with or that my
project would you help with and then the
end goal is to have a list of people who
want to help with projects might have an
idea of oh I want help with projects and
I'm good at marketing so I'm gonna tell
the system what I'm interested in and
then I'm good at marketing events it's
oh you said that you like you know since
making and marketing here's two
sense-making projects that need
marketing help so would it be fair to
say that your biggest need right now is
volunteers cific skillsets yeah now I
will say that's sort of the biggest
thing that I like that I need help with
that also I think this can reasonably
solve in the near future like an obvious
thing that a lot of projects need is
money where you know the end goal of
this might end up being something like a
patreon for projects like this a couple
of people have talked about that we've I
think at least one project it's sort of
talking about maybe starting that but in
my mind that you know if you had
something like I think most of us are
thinking of together tech as we have
some different ideas as to like what
features might end up being there but
the end idea of helping projects sort of
tell the need that's everything from
just building your audience of people
who want to know what you're up to
to building you know an army of
volunteers who can actually help the
build it grate it to having audience and
volunteers or whatever group it is
actually starting to contribute either a
one-time or a monthly payment much of a
patreon and again that that last thing I
don't think that you'd want to try to
tackle yet so so so add riyals biggest
need is fun tears with specific skill
sets so but Jubilee I think yours is
different right yeah mine's
participation so any volunteer who wants
to be
part of an online video conversation and
then if they're higher than that like
not sorry also I would love to record
them and put them on lines people are
more willing to do that and but just
participation and people knowing when
there is something they can participate
in and especially if that can be so I
guess it's not marketing it's like if
they can know when something that's more
route like it then their time schedule
and it's within their area of interest
right
what does does that work for them those
people who would participate in any
solution raising as long as it's on the
schedule there's other people who will
make the time in their schedule for a
specific topic and it figuring that
piece out but I kind of think that what
we're doing right now which is a project
raising on together tech what I want to
do is offer a solution raising on
projects is like what do we currently do
when you have an idea to get into the
world what would our deal look like and
then what is something we can do at ten
thousand people in hundred thousand
dollars but that's not what we need to
determine this period but I'm just
putting it out there that that is what
I'm sparking is like doesn't matter if
you have a project or not if you did how
would you get into the world and and
it's creating a solution raising on that
okay how the human I think for me I just
need time so if I was gonna need
anything right at the moment it would be
another developer to do code reviews and
pair programming with on the topic and
kind of review things or speed up with
some of the simpler stuff that's not the
core logic of the system which you know
everyone can use more software
developers these days so I'm not gonna
hold back after that then it will be a
community organizer would be ideal so I
guess it does come down to people which
of course you can either get through
volunteers or through funding
so yeah I mean those so I mean those are
the things we keep talking about but I
think it's good to know specifically
like jubblies need is a little different
from ours because we need specifics it's
what I think one leads to the other like
I think you don't get a volunteer with
felt building an audience first because
I don't think people are going to like
just show off and be like I want to do
work for polar reason score unless they
know of reason score is they've been
following it for a while they're
interested and they say oh they need
quarters I'm a coder right or like if
you're if you're following be projects
and just sort of Lucy bingo what's going
on over there well they want people to
go on camera to talk to talk about
education that sounds cool well I think
you can build a broad audience then try
and pull people out of it but I think
there are also ways to specifically seek
out people of a certain type and
focusing your efforts on those people
right yeah I think that's sort of like
broad marketing versus like guerilla
marketing where it's the end goal is to
get people on board and whether it's you
know you just put an ad on Facebook or
you went to like a local game B group
and got people to sign up at the end of
the day especially you know for the
first 200 users for the MVP it's
probably mostly going to be that v1 on
one it's going to be going up to
Facebook groups you know on and YouTube
videos and leaving comments and inviting
people and both you know the project
owners and the B volunteers and I think
yeah I think I was I wasn't necessarily
thinking was MVP but now that I've heard
both of you talk about sounds like it
definitely is is the ability to say what
you're interested in like things like
sense making and then on projects say
like to categorize them so Beth as an
audience member you can just say I'm
interested you know in this area I than
any new projects that come on we can
also say oh by the way you said you were
excited in sense-making and we have two
new sensor making projects if you want
to check those out so that's sort of one
level of notification that's not
civically project-based like it's not
like saying hey recent score has a a new
video that you should just check out but
kind of like what one of the earliest
almost most important parts of it is
just the sort of match people up saying
you said that you were you know a
volunteer you've got these skills which
that part might even be sort of like I
think it's MVP but not like earliest
earliest version where at first it would
just be here you know I want to sign up
as either a member for a project person
but the project says what categories did
they fit into and then the the volunteer
says what categories are interested in
and then it sort to build a list to say
hey your stuff you said that you you you
might be interested in and whether
you're already following it or not
projects we put out a survey that then
got made into a spreadsheet on that that
same thing but instead of on your
project on you write what are you
interested in with multiple choice
options so that we you know sense-making
food education things that are that are
more categorizing and then also like is
if there's a way to contact people
whenever there's a new sense making
thing right maybe they've heard of wiki
lecture and they're interested in
everything wiki lection does but then
you already have that contact so you can
contact them directly but anytime
there's a new one they want to be they
want to be talked about anyway so sorry
what they're interested in as well as
what their skills are right like like
could you do coding right like or is it
just anyone who's interested in
sense-making you want to be able to pull
a thousand people like how do we grow
our pool of participants for all of them
right whether you have a project or not
and then how do we focus so that we can
we can notify them when there is eight
event going on or when you're a project
holder if you have a specific request of
them right like you can send out to
people who are interested in
sense-making and they have the skill of
coding you can send out an email saying
hey we're looking for someone to put in
four hours look over this code right you
need to be volunteer and you're you're
Martin it's gonna be targeted marketing
then right it's gonna have the skills
and have that and the more we're able to
build that face and not piss them off
right not send them everything every
time
but we were trying to focus it and
listening to that feedback as well of
whoops what you sent you too many in the
last last while right like how do we
build that base for all of our projects
and hone it in a way where we're sending
the right requests and information to
the right people right so one option for
that might be to use something like
MailChimp which has a fairly large free
level and then you can you can ask
questions when they sign up and then
send out emails based upon their answers
and I think they have a multiple choice
or checkboxes or something in there yeah
so that's one option there might be
competitors that would do the same thing
this is where it would be great if there
was more than three of us participating
with our projects right some we'd know
more of what people need and more of
what but in creating it in a way where
any of us can Twitter to tweet it or put
it on Facebook where we're building the
audience we're building that group of
people right it doesn't matter whether
they're my high school friend or your
cousin or like it's like what are you
interested in knowing what is it like to
have more concentrated marketing on
things already so that's our second so
what I think I'm hearing from that is
whatever content goes in there so let's
say like definitely comes out with a new
you know a write-up on reason score or a
video or some kind of content that he
says great I want to share this with
people to get some interest in this case
he might you know either upload it or
like somehow put it on together Tech
it's now at least part of it is public
so he can then take that link put it on
Facebook and say hey you know we've
reason scores just released a new video
people who click on that link will be
taken to some sort of like a
public-facing hey here's the content
that that reason score just shared you
can you know you can read it you can
watch the video do whatever but it's
within together text so at that point
the person can if they want they could
go in like oh I want to go take a look
at the reason score profile and see what
that what that project is up to and you
can go and see you know a recent
timeline
all the stuff there with the end goal
being somebody says oh this is cool I
like this I like together tech I want to
sign up on together tech so that I can
follow reason score yeah possibly it's
it's yeah it's building that base
audience for if whether it's together
tech bringing an inner solution raising
bringing it in as long as the person is
interested they're gonna want to know
whether it about what they're interested
in as long as they have their skill set
we're gonna want to pair them with where
they where they want to go so any time
anyone's brought in that they're part of
the bigger group of people a bigger I
don't know what the word is like group
of people to pick from right but you
could don't I don't want to send out
every video I do to 10,000 people and
annoy them I want it to be more focused
but that pool pool is the word I'm
looking for that pool of potential
Watchers the the pool of potential
participants and as well as volunteers
having them opt into that to say here's
what I actually want to know about
here's what I want to participate in
maybe they don't want to miss paid on
camera so there's other things that I
could put out you know they mean like
the more we can get that information
from them in a survey the more we can
hone how do we how do we all use that
pool and have people opt in so that all
of the project all the projects in game
be projects and together tech can
benefit from that pool of people without
pissing off that pool with people right
yeah I think the like cadence wise I
think it would be up to the project
owners you know so we'll probably have
some guidelines a cape maybe don't send
more than two or three messages a week
like just in general and then for the
actual like for together tech doing that
hey stuff you might be interested in I
think to start with we would just do
that once a week like you know what once
we actually have enough content we'd say
hey you're you know we had 10 new
projects last week three of them aligned
with your interests here's what those
three projects are the way I had
envisioned it if they want to follow a
specific project then I would almost
want that project to have except the
Jubilees point of directing people to
the central together tech to get more
info on all the all the projects
it might be good to have those be
separate email lists or what you know
whatever the thing is I guess it depends
on whether we're doing an MVP with
existing tariffs or creating our own
tech yeah the the current goal is to be
creating our own tech because it's like
well not going to be hiring a coder and
then you know no I think the current
goal is to get the need filled and I
don't think you know if we could do it
with MailChimp why not deal with the
MailChimp for free yeah if it can meet
all of the different pieces everything
just the MVP be is important in MVP
right just an email well we can do that
now well no but a way where you can show
interest in different topics and then
get notifications when those top who you
know when something new happens under
that topic that is doable in MailChimp
today for free yet for less than 12,000
emails a month right I just like think
that you have to have a lot more on top
of that in order to actually drive
people to to to personally yeah yep but
we can also so what we could do in
MailChimp to make it at MVP is to have a
newsletter and have it be something that
is both powerful for the projects that
they want to update so having something
that has a regular what's their word
template where it's like here's here's
all the projects they're involved right
click here to like go and get your
update if that's something of interest
and here's a new product here's all the
new projects and have them categorized
so that your guyses is under sense
making the nice ones render and then
also potentially I don't know there to
be a weekly or monthly newsletter cuz
things happen really rapidly but like
here's what's going on in here's this
calendar of events going on in the next
month right of like if you want
participate reasons for here's what's
going on in wiki lectures what's going
on and but it's one newsletter right so
it's going to go out without that
codified but but the newsletter itself
is generated in a way that breaks it
down to your interest right you're not
going to care about the non education
ones right or if you're only into
education but just see that and then
it's also generating people signing up
the newsletter people with projects can
send out that newsletter to their people
to bring them on to the newsletter and
it's building that pool of people I
guess I don't I don't see what the value
of having a high regular repeating
newsletter the goal is that we can we
can send people sub place so we could
say hey if you're interested in helping
out projects and you have any of these
skill sets or any of these interests go
to this link and fill it in and we will
you will get an email when something
happens I think that's good as far as a
Minimum Viable Product project and our
that I don't think there's much I mean
that I don't I don't see why we'd add
the extra complexity of having a regular
newsletter no I was just like it kind of
fulfills the need for for just MailChimp
to have that next layer of like here's
like having it in sections where it's
like if you want to follow your favorite
project here's all the projects they're
involved maybe that's at the very end
because it is the thing that would be
generating constantly but also like here
if you're a coder here it's what we need
right here's where we need volunteers
here's where we need skillset and so it
would go out to people who but the more
we can hone that so that it's not one
newsletter that goes out to everyone the
same the ideas that we don't have a pool
of people yet so great to create that
pool of people it's a more generalized
newsletter that is like look at all
these projects and how they're involved
I'll say I agree with Bentley in that to
me newsletters don't make sense
simply because each email sucks like
people open up maybe 1% of emails that
they receive even if you sign up and
want to see it very likely gets lost
amongst the witch even like to have
email notifications for it that's more
like an hoping that there's going to be
a couple of them and you have a higher
chance to to see one I think that
becomes like a small sliver and then we
talk about ways to improve it and well I
think that if we can do this with a
collection of tools that's a good start
starting point personally my like the
goal here is to actually come up with
the Minimum Viable
product with something that's actually
built and it's not pretty it's not you
know it probably doesn't even have 5% of
the features it will end up with but but
it's just saying like what's actually
interesting and easy enough that we
could possibly do this you know like
drop the the specs and my eventual goal
is to pay out-of-pocket for actually a
coder to come in and and code this what
is that code adapt look look like and
then for things like it might just be
you know using an API to talk to to a to
MailChimp or someone so we don't have to
reinvent the email wheel that's fine but
so i guess my thing is well what does
that product have to look like so that
we like we as product owners would
actually want to sign up and we as
people who are interested helping other
projects that that part appeal stuff to
us as well is if we only have one i
guess technically we could just start
out with projects and almost sort of
make it like a project directory we're
not sure why projects would come on
board if there isn't that flipside of oh
and by the way the end goal of its is
that you get help with your project i
think if we have people that are
interested projects and we're telling
people projects will come on board I
don't think finding the projects is is
the challenging bet I think the hard
part's finding the volunteers and I you
you were kind of saying that email sucks
but I think all the solutions we've been
discussing or email so I don't know what
you're proposing how's that I'm saying
email becomes one prong as it right so
I'm not saying don't do email I'm just
saying don't put a lot of work into
making email work as a system knowing
that like I've signed up for newsletters
and then you know open them once or
twice and then just lost interest for a
while and now I see that same news that
are hopping up that I might open well
you know once a month now do you wanna
thinking of is that daily e-newsletter
which we were talking about but still
well yeah but if you're if you're only
getting an email when something new
happens and it's not a recurring thing
which has other risks then you're more
likely to open it up I think unless you
I think it depends on the person right
like just if you email too often you're
likely to get unsubscribed for
sure if you like well they'll forget
about that they signed up for the emails
the yeah yeah I mean they do talk about
keeping email lists warm and stuff but
you know that there's a risk both ways
that this sort of thing but if our goal
is to just is just to have a
notification system that we can you know
a place the word we could have a list of
people that have interests and their
skills that then we can notify them when
either new projects come about or you
know a project significantly changes or
has a new need then then I think we can
we can do that but that's different from
having a project directory yeah that's a
different feature so the thing that I do
like about that is like the way that I
am planning and I think for wiki
election there's no around this for
together tech it might be possible is I
really don't want to get people another
freaking login like that part to me is
like I just really if people have to
remember another login or another
password that's just another barrier to
entry that is something I do like about
that system about like just using
MailChimp in a survey is as long as you
know you can just say here's my email I
mean it says great what do you want us
to sign up for it's very low low
friction as far as getting people to
sign up and manage their I do like that
about it we not use the Facebook and
Google logins I know they're not ideal
for when Facebook when we know that is
that's to me quite considering I try to
we're trying to create a like technology
cooperative but it competes the ball why
are you trying to use them like that's
where the people are and that's I'm with
discord is they don't have that and so
it's a new login every time that
somebody sends you a link to do to do it
it doesn't it doesn't really realize
that I'm going to I'm the same person
that you know what excited for the
cooperative's as game be as this you
know and so for that but I feel like
creating an MVP that's out that's not
just an email list like that
that is doable and we could you know
generate something else but if we're
actually coding something outside of
Facebook and Google and those is we
don't have the people and so creating
something is expensive and
time-consuming when we don't have the
people to say here's what I want out of
it and here's what what what this is
which we might be able to generate more
of that by doing or at least solutions
that are generative through a project
raising on it
but all of it is gonna come down to how
do we actually get 10,000 people right
like how do we our a thousand or 100 any
a number right like how do we actually
keep create something that people want
to come to because I don't really want
to sign up for another email list right
I'm not like oh now that is wait whereas
something like a patreon that's actually
designed around projects where I can be
like people can request things of me and
I can do surveys and things that are
that sounds much more fun but yeah then
it's not MVP right like then it's like
okay well and so that's where to me the
10,000 and people and $100,000 is to me
where I'm focusing my energy because
it's like once and that's what I'm
excited about cuz that's sort of been
sitting with this week is looking
through the solution raising so I'm like
now that we have several of them I want
to do one more on labor and then I want
to do one on solution raising and but
it's and then which means how do we
actually get 10,000 people right and how
do we work with 10,000 people and how do
we do that so I think that's an
interesting part is and this is where
building MVPs is always interesting
because there's not like it's such a
nebulous term for a lot of people I
think the M in the V or in you know
stark contrast with each other where you
want to make it as minimal as possible
but it has to be viable so if people if
you have a tool but nobody will use it
it's not viable they're like great you
have an app it sucks thanks for building
that that they help no one but if you
build it over the top and you're like
great that's too much and the feature
don't make sense you didn't get feedback
or earlier enough so what does it look
like like for us to actually say and you
it any of these projects are going to
have that really weird uncomfortable
time where
if you build something you're not gonna
start up with users even if you have an
email list and then you know you have a
thousand people and you build an app and
say oh hey everyone we just built an app
go and sign up a lot of them probably
won't a part you guys they didn't see
the email or they just you know don't
want to create another login whatever
that reason is there's gonna be that
process for you again and have to get
people to now sign up on the app so if
we have a sort of a stepping stone of
like using a survey to build a list of
people who hears your interest and
here's your year your skill set if we
can find a way to make that viable I
like it because it's it's fast that we
can do that now without having to code
something but I think for the actual
like the the Minimum Viable Product
where it's not somebody else's product
is sort of the first stepping stone up
together to take itself like the actual
building up the product what is that
look look look like this Dennison so
you're asking what is the first when we
actually do write code what's it look
like is that your right like if we have
some sort of an app on together techcom
that's trying to I think we can all sort
of agree we're trying to like there's
gonna be some sort of like a profile for
the projects and then some sort of a way
to sort of build an audience and from
that audience hopefully get some
volunteers and start to so you sort of
do both sides for projects you can get
help and you can you know speak to your
audience and start to build that
somewhere outside of the areas that
there's not really a good spot for it
now like yeah you can do it on Facebook
but Nick I think that for me what's
coming up is the minimal Viable Product
will be just that having a place where I
could say hey I'm Jubilee here so we can
go to get more information on me I'm you
know trying to create solution raising
in the world here's it's minimal Viable
Product right now right which is a
Facebook group and here you can follow
my update videos right monthly on our
Facebook page if you want you know you
can join our Facebook page and creating
a way that then as people and then a way
for people to sign up to say hey I want
to say keep updated on the other tech I
want to keep updated on
crazy I wanna get keep updated and read
some score so that if I have something
new I can send it out right that's so I
don't think it's what you said but it's
something that I sort of heard in the
beginning of it where I think we've all
sort of talked about the concept of you
know of course we're gonna be tracking
projects and there's gonna be some
capacity for members to follow a project
but if you think about like so for
example somebody like Jubilee was a part
of project raising she was a part of
solution raisings who joins all these
other sessions or somebody like me or
Bentley where we have wiki election a
reason score then we're also a part of
together tech you have a page for the
profile but also the page for the person
and you can follow either like if
somebody says Julie's smart she you know
has it you know insight in a whole broad
range of topics I'm interested to see
anything that that she does and so even
if like a video on wiki election Julie's
a part of it somebody might get alerted
just because of that
just because Jubilee is a part of it and
they are following her as like you know
a person as opposed to a certain project
where that you also have to be able to
follow like that sorry Bradley go I'll
write my note so what's the value of
putting that in this app rather than
using what's already out there I mean if
people want to see everything that
Jubilee does they could follow her on
Twitter if you post everything that's
something but that's up to her you know
I'm just saying why are we inviting
social media is a part to store the
content because right now if she wants
to put right if she wants to write a
blog post where is she putting that well
on medium on on the hundred blog posting
systems and so then that's purely for
content and then you okay here's the
website here's the twitter here's all
these different channels it's sort of
meant to be as much as it can be which
is a long way to down the road actually
that useful sort of it one-stop shop if
you put you your content here but the
idea is to build your audience here sort
of like ah it's almost like a pre
patreon where it's like you're starting
to build your audience it's gonna end up
being we want to build a future where
your audience can choose just to to
support you here for this specific thing
for like a very purpose
in patreon and then it also is for
storing your content it's for sort of
being able to have here's your one spot
where you've got your profile you've got
this it's hopefully going to end up
helping you achieve on your project and
then you would go on to Facebook on to
Twitter on to your website on your
medium on to all these places where
you're trying to to to funnel them in
that direction like I'm not sure how
many channels you have Bentley I know I
have a challenge in wiki election of
trying to figure out like we were to put
stuff and I've got channels on YouTube
on Twitter on facebook on patreon I
don't use all of them I just kind of
reserved them so that I can use them at
some point but there's still the where
does this go where do I put this and if
it's a YouTube video it's easy but for a
lot of other things we go really one on
the website I could but then I have to
go and like get a wordpress plug-in to
have a blog and I don't really care if
that's on the website I like the idea
because it does help us build that
audience with them I'll have Bentley
sent to you that we are a little bit
reinventing the wheel but it's because
of this like there are block chain
people that are trying to solve this for
like you post it one place you can
decide where it is but that's not really
like our main audience right our 10,000
people that hopefully grows from there
is that I am all over the place so I'm
on some of this content isn't available
because it's unlisted but some of the
content maybe I could make for my
subscribers right make me like the stuff
on the break mankind's YouTube channel
which is our Omega group stuff but if I
go to a podcast and then and then it
links back right if Jordan Hall it talks
to many people and we can follow you
know you can see where all of them all
of the places Jordan Hall has been and
then you can connect that for if you
want to follow the person you can see
all of their content but you're also
bringing people into the pool like if so
I'm just like somehow because I've had a
conversation with Jordan Hall and people
are defined that then it brings an
audience to me which means then because
I'm here I bring an audience to you guys
right like looks like if people suddenly
don't mean like Jordan halls can have a
much bigger audience than I am of course
on everyone who wants to Orton Hall and
sees our interview is going to like yes
I want to follow Jubilee but then when
I'm on something that isn't even part of
together tech isn't even part of ours it
draws in their audience of it or and
especially if they know that a part of
their like
oh I didn't know I could you know Joe
Romans not gonna sign up for it but like
the other little little places or maybe
he will because he wants to help other
projects right to say hey where do we
find out about good ideas that are there
and how do we share in that like Twitter
is not there to help us share in our
audience right you have to pay to grow
your audience you have to pay to to you
I can't just follow all the game B
people easily but I can't just upload
content say hey this is just me ranting
about WestJet don't worry about it
this is nothing to do with like me and
my bigger vision of the world but a lot
of this content is and most of the
content is but this idea Cafe on on
autism isn't right it's like but if you
want to follow and that piece like not
just me but maybe you want to follow my
autistic journey or maybe you want to
follow because I've had brain damage or
you like breaking people down but it's
like actually being able to find then I
can find all of the times we've talked
about trust right not just you believe
it I want to follow trust like there's
so many ways to categorize this it is
like the data pool that as a user I can
I can get more access to you and then
all the things we can we can build off
of that but isn't and it is a fairly
minimal Viable Product right where it's
like just a profile and like it doesn't
start with all of that it's just a
person and project and here's all the
places where I have been wet and it's
sort of like a squat to store the
content where they're saying they're
talking about that project these three
people but it's just like here's the
content here's who's involved there's I
found that back-end to it but the front
end is just your tracking projects your
tracking people and then like how they
interrelate and the content that gets
created I guess the the risk I see what
that is now it's another channel I have
to maintain because I'm not going to
have that as my barrier because I think
having everyone's content sourced out of
a single place is risky so died and you
know I'd like the idea of having a place
where we can build off each other's
audiences but I didn't see how having a
place for us to store content does that
those are two separate things and that
they're not directly what is an actually
it might not be MVP I think we want it
at some point but I agree it's not net
Sara Lee MVP it's not you know we
couldn't hear it but it's like what
which I you know I think it took us a
while to to get here but it's good what
is that so if we're saying that there's
like they're following a person and
their content or that maybe that's not
MVP I think it's cool but yeah maybe but
so MVP guaranteed you have to have a
project page or what else is it's just
it really is just hard to be Facebook ad
that point it just like when there's
there's nothing to do you would just
sign up for a profile I have nothing to
do so I think it's there's members
there's projects you can follow a
project there's I think there was
something I think you had said Bentley
where you're sort of like getting around
to you know you can post it on Twitter
and and you would need some way to say
like here's a public facing side so I
can put a link on Twitter and on these
other channels you say hey go check out
this did this video or blog post or
whatever now that sort of leads back in
that is that part the minimum viable if
we just have a project page of people
following a project but there's no
capacity for like the project to provide
updates is that useful well okay yeah
let's take even a step for the back so
like we we figured out that it'd be nice
to be notified when something happens
within your interest area and in a skill
set that you have and then now we're
saying we would like to have a place
that when someone first goes there they
can kind of see a live result of that
same search like what's happened in the
past without the notification ROI the
main thing right yeah so you want to go
and say here's what I'm here's what I'm
interested in and here's my skill set
what's what in the past has happened and
and so a MailChimp solution wouldn't
solve that I can't think of any way
using the existing technology and then I
think you'd be like here's the last five
who knew there's we've sent out in case
you're interested well it no I mean
here's the last
it would be here's the last or the
complete history of everything that
matches what you selected right all
right okay so yes that's a feature we
don't have oh yeah
that history and that's something that
just because of how this is being built
will end up being able to do that part
of it I mean if we can't then the whole
thing sunk anyway that's a one of the
main things I'm interested to think what
you think either from a project side or
like a volunteer side that relationship
between person and project not the
project owner just either somebody who's
interested in or what the volunteer what
sort of the smallest thing that we can
do that would actually be interesting is
that I think it is important to realize
we are reading the wheel we're just sort
of adding one or two extra spokes to put
it you know it's a special spin on it
but effectively yeah this is kind of
like trying to reinvent Facebook /
patreon / some of that stuff really it's
very patreon asked at its core there's
just a bunch of extra stuff on top
that's important and to start out with
there won't be a payment thing because
that really complicates it but in my
mind we're building towards that point
like that sort of one of the end points
is having a be that ecosystem that
patreon asked but we're instead of being
like a creator of like entertainment
which typically in my experience is what
patreon is for this is specifically
around like game D projects so what is
that need
I mean I'd my I guess my philosophy
ongoing or be that we identified the
most important need and try and solve
that need rather than having this target
go cuz I think our target is I'd kind of
disagree with that we're creating
patreon for projects what would you guys
think I would rather not have that
destination so we can find it on our
path there so I'd rather go agile rather
than waterfall I guess this was like a
job the project has an purpose a purpose
not a feature set your listing a feature
set not
true but even have a road map and road
maps do contain that like we'll try to
do these road maps are very very very
loose the looser the better the less of
a road map the better a road map is just
because businesses need it not because
that gel needs it so at anytime that
we're saying oh we're heading towards
this goal that is something that I am
cautious about and want to bump against
is that we need to say what's our next
Eisley we only have like four minutes
but like what is it pursued a purpose
and a goal well no I was sitting the
difference between a purpose and a I'll
go and a feature right we're listing
actual features our purpose is to sort
of help projects and help drive that
forward morning I think what we actually
wants just like the ten thousand a
hundred thousand is what I want for
solution raising is and we want at least
a dozen people who have projects that
are similar and not similar who can come
together and say what do we want in our
version of patreon or whatever that
looks like right like how do we find
people and have these same conversations
that are generative but like that is
actually our MVP is we need to be able
to have a what does that look like and
right now it looks like our ice live on
video but maybe it does it any people
really aren't comfortable that so doing
the Facebook page and saying bump this
up give us make this your number one
notification of that it's right if that
resonates with you and then also what
does getting together weekly look like
right like does it look like an hour on
Saturday mornings what would that
generate like what is it going on zoom
and then breaking off into groups that
are appropriate to yours like what do
you want in an MVP but then also having
just that discussion like just eat how
do we bring people to one of those
conversations so we can be a dozen
people having that conversation most
projects
so doodle pool on times for the first
conversation I don't know I agree with
all that I did want to point out that
that's in the last several minutes is
completely different from what we've
discussed for the last hour but that's
good the reset I mean maybe the main
thing is we need more than three people
before we jump down building anything
but yeah I think we do and we yet we
have 50 people in projects and I
guarantee you there are at least a dozen
projects in that if not 20 or 30 and so
finding a time for 12 of those to meet
shouldn't be that difficult especially
right now we're on lockdown right like
maybe you couldn't make Tuesday morning
at 10 a.m. but right now you can put off
whatever you're doing online for that
time and actually meet extend your
workday longer right like there's people
have more ability to do those type of
things right now so if we put our two
doodle pull for when would you actually
come and be part of a zoom conversation
that is recorded but not live and
generate what are the top what is the
the thing that's stopping your project
what would an MVP look like what would
and we can maybe hash out a little more
of what that looks like for us right
what does that medium look like what
kind of questions do we want to answer
so that we have that purpose what is the
purpose and then how do we actually
create an MVP for or that I think that's
perfect alright okay how does that
resonate with you a draw I was gonna
space down for the last that's alright
that's that I can't even get free
iterated Audrey watch it but you're like
I can real pretty conversation with more
than the three of us and how do we
actually do that because we keep trying
it keeps not happening but I like
listener what a step back what have we
do the same thing with more people
yeah I'll probably abandon the idea of
doing like trying to reuse the same code
stream that was kind of a part of it was
there's a lot of similarities between
the two projects at least like at the
base level but if it's not there yet if
we don't think that we're doing that
then that's fine we can you know
cross that bridge when we come to it
yeah I think what I would do is I'll put
our two doodle poll with several times
on it for our group you can also do I
think what I said about the algorithm
like changing your notification so this
one's up there because we're we need to
move fast on projects and we need you to
see them and then it'll pull for a time
then we can put that out to the bigger
game be community and even on Twitter
and stuff as well right you have a
project you want to move forward that
maybe not it's this criteria routes the
world then really in any way come be
part of having a conversation on how we
generate those projects yeah and also
ask them if they're if they're not going
to participate why or what what could we
do to have them participate yeah it's
just a scheduling thing or is it because
it zoom is it yeah yeah I like that too
why not no all right I might not be able
to do that this right away because I'm
trying to solve all of the world's
problems with it well on vacation well I
like all this stuff but um it also might
happen within the next week as I'm
trying to sequester myself away from lab
family what a great time to do this all
right should we say goodbye to YouTube
and Facebook all right buddy